A romantic adventure for the dangerous at heart.
Shanghai Surprise is a romance, adventure, crime film directed by Jim Goddard.
Glendon Wasey is a fortune hunter looking for a fast track out of China.
Gloria Tatlock is a missionary nurse seeking the
curing powers of opium for her patients.
Fate sets them on a hectic, exotic, and even romantic quest for stolen drugs.
But they are up against every thug and smuggler in Shangai.
Glendon Wasey, played by Sean Penn.
Gloria Tatlock, played by Madonna.
Walter Faraday, played by Paul Freeman.
Willie Tuttle, played by Richard Griffiths.
Joe Go, played by Clyde Kusatsu.
Justin Kronk, played by Philip Sayer.
Shanghai Surprise is a 1986 adventure comedy film directed by Jim
Goddard and starring then-newlyweds Sean Penn and Madonna.
The screenplay was adapted by John Kohn and Robert Bentley from
Tony Kenrick's 1978 novel Faraday's Flowers.
Produced by George Harrison's HandMade Films and distributed by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, Harrison himself appears in
the film as a night club singer, and he wrote and recorded five original songs for the soundtrack.
The film was a critical and commercial failure, and an
official soundtrack album was never released.
The film explores themes of china, shanghai, china, american abroad.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.